Gustavo Meza Hinojo

Lima, Perú

(+51) 943 265 180 | gustavo.meza@pucp.edu.pe

Economist graduated from the Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú, with two years of professional experience in consulting, research and economic analysis. Throughout my professional experience I have developed reports, presentations and academic documents based on data analysis. I have experience in managing databases and estimates of econometric models.

Education

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú (PUCP)

07/2020

• Bachelor degree

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú (PUCP)

In progress

• Specialization diploma in data science for social sciences

Work experience

SEMANAeconómica

11/2023-04/2023

Economics and financial analyst

• Economic analysis for the preparation of articles related to macroeconomic and financial issues, especially monetary policy, fiscal policy, international economy, employment, poverty, private and public investment.

Junior Researcher 01/2022 - 10/2022

GĚRENS Graduate School – Research Direction

- Achievements at GĚRENS (includes previous experience): I participated in the direct elaboration of 13 consulting projects, 9 research projects and 5 blog articles.
- Formulation and development of academic research on energy economics and mining economics.
- Preparation of regulatory analysis reports, economic analysis and financial analysis of the sectors: hydrocarbons, electricity and mining.

Consulting assistant 12/2020 - 12/2021

GÉRENS School of Management and Economics – Economic Consulting

- Preparation of academic presentations on topics relevant to the national economy: taxation of mining operations, taxation of hydrocarbon operations, pension systems, contributions of mining to the national economy, contributions of the hydrocarbon sector to the national economy and regional economies, among others.
- Database processing for the analysis of the mining, electricity and hydrocarbons sectors.

Professional Intern 08/2020 - 11/2020

GÉRENS Graduate School – Research Direction

- Assistance for the preparation of research papers and academic presentations on energy economics and mining economics.
- Collection and management of databases, literature review, application of statistical and econometric methodologies, and writing of academic papers related to mining and energy economics.

Intern 02/2020 - 07/2020

GÉRENS School of Management and Economics – Economic Consulting

 Assistance for the preparation of research papers and academic presentations on energy economics and mining economics.

Intern 07/2019 - 01/2020

INDECOPI – Secretaría Técnica de la Comisión de Defensa de la Libre Competencia

- Assistance for the preparation of reports and studies on the conditions of competition in the port sector and international maritime transport of cargo in Peru.
- Assistance for the processing of databases as part of the antitrust investigations.

Specialization Programs

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú (PUCP)

02/2022 - 03/2022

• Advanced Applied Econometrics (Impact Evaluation)

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú (PUCP)

01/2022 - 03/2022

• Training in Python Fundamentals for Social Science and Public Management

Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú (PUCP)

09/2017 - 11/2017

• STATA for economics

Additional Information

Idiomas Católica 11/2016

• Advanced English

Computing: MS Office (Excel, Power Point, Word), Stata (Advanced), Python (Intermediate), R (Intermediate), Eviews (Intermediate).

References

PhD. Arturo Vásquez Cordano

Director de Investigación GĚRENS Escuela de Posgrado Mail: avasquez@gerens.pe